<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;4 Tīrthayātrā on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;4 Tīrthayātrā on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>11 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/11_Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/11_Introduction/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XI
TIRTHAYĀTRĀ (pilgrimages to holy places)
All religions have laid great emphasis on the sacredness of certain localities and have either ønjoined or recommended with great insistence pilgrimages to them. Among the five incumbent practical religious duties1237 of a Moslem, pilgrimage at least once in kis life to Mecoa and Medina, the birth place and burial place of the prophet Mohammad, is one. The four places of pilgrimage for Buddhists have been the place of the birth of Buddha ( Lumbini or Rumpindei), the place where he attained perfect enlightenment (Bodh Gayā), the place where he set in motion the wheel of dharma by delivering his first sermon (at Sārnāth near Benares ) and the place where he passed away into the state of nirvana (Kusinārā).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 The Ganges</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/12_The_Ganges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/12_The_Ganges/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XII
THE GANGES
Since the Ganges is the holiest of rivers and since such highly esteemed tirthas as Kanakhala, Haridvāra, Prayāga and Kāśi are situated on it, it would be most proper to begin the treatment of individual tirthas with the Ganges,
It has been already seen (p. 556) how the Ganges is the first among the many rivers invoked in the famous Nadistutz hymn (Rg X.75 5-6). In Rg 1323 VI 45 31 we have the word &amp;lsquo;Gangyah&amp;rsquo; which most probably means &amp;lsquo;growing on the Ganges&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 Kāśī</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/13_kAshI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/13_kAshI/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XIII
KAŚĪ
There is hardly any city in the world that oan olain greater antiquity, greater continuity and greater popular Veneration than Banaras. Baparas has been a holy city for at least thirty centuries. No city in India arouses the religious emotions of Hindus as much as Kāśi does. To the Hindu mind it represents great and unbroken traditions of religious sanctity and learning. It is a miniature of Hindu life through the ages in all its great complexities and contradictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 Gayā</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/14_gayA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/14_gayA/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XIV
GAYA
Gaya occupies a unique place in the hearts of all pious Hindus eren in these days. Hundreds of pages bave been written about the history, the antiquities, the architectural remains of Gavā, the sacred places in and round about Gayā, the sraddha rites performed in Gaya and about Gayawals (the priests of Gaya). It is not possible to deal with this vast mass in this worko Bat it is impossible not to say a few words about the many conflicting views on certain important matters put forward by scholars for about three quarters of a century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Kurukṣetra and Other Famous Tīrthas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/15_kuruxetra_and_Other_Famous_tIrthas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/15_kuruxetra_and_Other_Famous_tIrthas/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XV
KURUKSETRA AND SOME OTHER FAMOUS
TĪRTHAS
KURUKSETRA (25 miles east of Ambala) is a very sacred tract, the history of which is lost in the mists of anti quity. In the Rgveda X.33.4 there is a reference to a king Kuruśravada, son of Trasadasyu.1538 The Atharva-veda men. tions a Kauravya husband (probably a king) who had a talk with his wife 2539 In the times of the Brāhmadas Kuruksetra had become a very holy land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 List of Tīrthas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/16_List_of_tIrthas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/4_tIrthayAtrA/16_List_of_tIrthas/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XVI - - LIST OF TĪRTHÁS
This is merely a list of tirthas from the point of view of Dharmaśāstra and not a treatise on the Ancient Geography of India. The result is that many countries and towns that have no importance or claims as tirthas have been altogether omitted. Bauddha and Jain works on tirthas have only rarely been referred to Many of the Puranas enumerate the moun tains and rivers of drīpas and ursas other than those of Jambudvīpa and Bhārata-yarsa such as Harivarsa, Ramyaka.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
