<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Pātaka, Prāyaścitta, Karmavipāka on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Pātaka, Prāyaścitta, Karmavipāka on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Pātaka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/01_pAtaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/01_pAtaka/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER I
The Article on sin in Hasting&amp;rsquo;s Encyclopædia of Religion and Ethics (Vol 11) will clearly show how the idea of sin varies from religion to religion, from age to age and from coun try to country. We are concerned here with the growth and development of the doctrine of sin in India from Vedic times to the medieval digests and commentaries on Dharmaśāstra
Sin (pātaku) is a word that belongs to the terminology of religion rather than to that of Ethics 1 It is very difficult to dafine sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Means of Reducing Consequences of Sins</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/02_Means_of_Reducing_Consequences_of_Sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/02_Means_of_Reducing_Consequences_of_Sins/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER II
MEANS OF REDUCING CONSEQUENCES OF SINS
Confession-In Āp. Dk S. 1. 9. 24. 15, 1. 10. 28. 19, 1. 10.29. 1 it is prescribed that the parson undergoing a penance for being an ableśasta or for unjustly forsaking his wife or for the murder of a learned brāhmana has to declara his misdeed while begging for alus to support himself. The Vedic student who was guilty of sexual intercourse had also to proclaim his lapse while begging at seven houses (Gaut, 23.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Prayaścitta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/03_prayashchitta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/03_prayashchitta/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER III PRAYAŚCITTA; ITS ORIGIN, DERITATION
AND JEANING
It is not necessary to turn to prayascittas as removers of sin, A mumber of subjects will fall to be trusted here.
First, an attempt inust be made to understand tlic etsnuo logy and meaning of the word &amp;lsquo;prayascitta&amp;rsquo; in ancient times There are two forms of the word, prāyascitti and prayascitta, which occur in Vedic works without distinction of meaning and both forms are sauly old, though payascitti appears to be the older of the two The form prāyascitti frequently occuis in the Tai, s (as in II.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Penances for Particular Sins</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/04_Penances_for_Particular_Sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/04_Penances_for_Particular_Sins/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER IV
PENANCES FOR PARTICULAR SINS
It is now proper to turn to the penances prescribed for individual sins of different types (grave sins, minor sins and the like). It may be noted that the smrtis contain numerous prāyaścittas for the same sin and that it is often difficult to reconcile all the dicta The commentaries and digests such as the Mit and the Prāgascitta-viveka therefore try to assign to each pobancs an appropriate provision, looking to all the circum stances noted above (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Names of All Prāyaścittas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/05_Names_of_All_prAyashchittas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/05_Names_of_All_prAyashchittas/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER V NAMES OF ALL PRĀYAŚCITTAS
Now all the prāyaścittas mentioned in the smrtis and digests will be arranged in alphabetical order (Sanskrit, transliterated into English), excepting mere hymns, fasts, &amp;amp;c. and brief explanations and references will be added to each.
AGHAMARSANA-(The hymn Rg. X 190 1-3)
This is prescribed as a penance for all sins by even the most ancient Dharmaśāstra works such as Gaut 24.11, Baud. Dh S IV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Consequences of Not Undergoing Penances</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/06_Consequences_of_Not_Undergoing_Penances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v4/1_pAtaka_prAyashchitta_karmavipAka/06_Consequences_of_Not_Undergoing_Penances/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER VI -
CONSEQUENCES OF NOT UNDERGOING PENANCES
If a sinner did not undergo a prāyaścitta, the Smrtis, Purāṇas, medieval digests declared that he had to suffer diro and far-Teaching consequences Yā). IL, 221 declares that men addicted to sins, vho feel no repentance and who (therefore ) do not undergo the proper penances, fall into painful and horri ble bells Manu XI, 54 ff and Yā). IIL 206 ff Provide that those guilty of grave (and other) sins after having passed numbers of years in hells and suffered the tortures of borrible hells are born again in this world because of (the remnants of their) svil actions in different forms such as lower animals, insects, trees and shrubs &amp;amp;c Manu XI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
