<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/0/</guid>
      <description>Preface PREFACE
The second volume of the History of Dharmaśāstra was published in the third quarter of 1941. In the Preface to that volume I held forth hopes that the next volume dealing with the remaining subjects comprised in Dharmaśāstra might be placed before scholars in about three years thereafter. The Great War was then being fought in Europe and it was generally believed that India would remain free from the fear of actual invasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Rājadharma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/1_rAjadharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/1_rAjadharma/</guid>
      <description>01 Introduction RĀJADHARMA
( GOVERNMENT AND STATECRAFT)
CHAPTER I
Rajadharma has been a subject of discussion in works on dharmasastra from very ancient times. The Āp. Dh. S. II. 9.25.1 says &amp;ldquo;The general and special dharnus of all varnas have been explained: but now we shall declare the dharmas of a king in particular! Āp. then states that the king should cause to be built a capital and a palace, the gates of which both should face the south; that the palace should be in the heart of the capital; that in front of the capital there was to be a hall called &amp;lsquo;aman trana&amp;rsquo; (hall of invitation); that to the south of the town there was to be an assembly house with doors on the north and south.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Vyavahāra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/2_vyavahAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/2_vyavahAra/</guid>
      <description>11 Introduction VYAVAHARA
(LAW AND ADMINISTRATION OF JUSTICE)
CHAPTER XI
That to administer justice impartially and to punish the guilty were among the prime functions of the sovereign has been stated above (p. 57). The king was deemed to be the fountain (i. e. the distributor ) of justice. Kautilya 323 (I. 19) prescribes that the king was to look into the disputes of citizens and country people in the 2nd part of the day (divided into eight parts ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Sadācāra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/3_sadAchAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/3_sadAchAra/</guid>
      <description>32 Introduction CHAPTER XXXII
SADACARA
CUSTOMS AND MODERN CUSTOMARY LAW1606
From Gautama 1606 downwards many writers dilate upon the sources of dharma. Gautama. I. 1-2 states: &#39; the Veda is the source ( mula) of dharma and also the tradition (or smṛtis ) and practice of those who know the Veda&#39;. Similarly Ap. Dh. S. (I. 1. 1.1-%) says: &amp;lsquo;we shall propound the acts (that produce merit) which are evolved from conventions and practices; the authority ( for finding out the dharmas) are the conventions of those who know the dharma and the Vedas&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/kANe/v3/4/</guid>
      <description>Appendix APPENDIX
NOTE 191 Long lists of high functionaries and other officers occur in several inscriptiong. Vide E. I. vol. VII at p. 91 (Kahla plate of Sodhadeva ), E. I. vol. XII at p. 40, E. I. vol, XIV at p. 327 ( grant of Mahipāla). There are about 40 titles in some ins criptions. They are generally arranged in order of dignity and importance, the highest coming first. Sometimes several offices are held by the same man.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
